The data provided here are all the one underlying the figures plotted in the main text.

1) validation_measurement.txt includes the data extracted from the laboratory measurement about the aspect ratio against the settling velocity for fiber with D = 47 um.

2) validation.txt includes all the data from both modeling and laboratory measurement for the validation plot.

3) fiber_sphere_comparision.txt includes the data for Fig 2c.

4) turbulence_effect40_high_no_turbulence_flat.txt includes the data for Fig 2d, in which high indicates high turbulent strength, flat indicates flat fiber, otherwise means round fiber. The naming applies the rest three files including the turbulence in the file name.

5) Field_measurement_data.xlsx includes the measured widths and lengths for the collected fiber, with the settling velocity calculated from our model.

6) aerodiameter.txt includes the aerodynamic sizes calculated for different definition for both flat and round fiber.

7) the size_small.txt includes the diameter and fraction for small particles for large-scale modeling, similar for the rest files beginning with the size as their file names.

8) source_attribution*.txt are the corresponding data for the source attribution for various particles.